Mark Lam

1770 Dean Street Brooklyn, New York USA markofthelam.com github.com/emceelamb

+1 661 478 9651 mlam@nyu.edu

I'm a sculptor, media scholar, and educator turned developer, with over five years experience developing websites and digital design for businesses ranging from e-commerce to independent artists. I research interdisciplinary interactive media to take a creative approach to computer networking technology. My other interests include teaching programming, digital accessibility, and making generative sound objects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Dynamic Web Development React, VueJS, Flask, Postgres, Mongodb
- Operations Automation (Bash, Python), *NIX System Administration
- Real-time Data Visualization D₃JS, Processing, P₅JS,
- Digital Accessibility Standards WCAG 2.1, Section 508

Professional Experience

2015– Mark of the Lam
Freelance Developer
NYC, HCMC, LA, Berkeley

- · Design and develop websites for business ranging from personal artists to independent publishing houses
- Implement web features including image api's to online payment procedure to streamline development time
- Scope timelines and specifications while coordinating with clients to meet business objectives
- · Work with account managers to deploy websites and test for bugs and errors

2018-2020 New York University - ITP

Graduate Assistant - Web Accessibility Developer

New York City

- Developed an accessibility compliant front-end interface for a project database to meet NYU accessibility initiative guidelines
- Created training materials to conduct accessibility audits with assistive tech including VoiceOver, Jaws, and Lighthouse/WAVE
- Mentored and trained students in web accessible programming paradigm
- · Assessed and correct digital accessibility issues in accordance to WCAG guidelines

1

2018–2019 Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts

Digital Accessibility Fellow

New York City

- · Created internal digital accessibility training material to promote access for a diverse customer base
- Created an automated work process for captioning a catalog of over 1000 hours of video content
- Audited internal and external digital media of a world-class performing arts institution and write recommendations to meet WCAG 2.1 and Section 508 compliance
- · Develop a fully compliant digital map of campus accessibility features to allow for increased physical access

2017–2018 HO CHI MINH CITY UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY & EDUCATION

Visiting Lecturer – Introductory Programming, English

Ho Chi Minh City

- Developed an introductory English/programming curriculum in the Clanguage for non-native English speaking students, and worked with student leaders to promote extracurricular English study
- · Led supplemental workshops in specialized programming topics such as web design and portfolio building

Education

May 2020 Interactive Telecommunications, Master of Professional Studies

New York University, New York City

Dec 2015 Media Studies & Art Practice, Bachelor of Arts

University of California, Berkeley, Berkeley

May 2013 Graphic Design, Associate of Arts

College of the Canyons, Valencia

Projects & Workshops

2020 **Bridge to the Internet**, Website, Open Source Software, Computer Networking *NYU ITP*, New York City

- Open Source router configuration built on Raspberry Pi
- · Website built with Vue.js explaining computer networking topics

2020 Automating Mindfully, Technical Workshop
Unconference at ITP NYU, New York City

- Introduction to Bash scripting language for beginner coders
- Explore automation as a meditative practice

2019 Lincoln Center Campus Accessibility Map, Digital Map

Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, New York City

- Created a digital map of the Lincoln Center Campus that is fully compliant to WCAG 2.1 standards
- Extended Google Maps API to incorporate WAI-ARIA features

2